<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homework on Data Science for Biotechnology</title>
    <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homework on Data Science for Biotechnology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week01/</guid>
      <description>Week 1: Introduction to the Course  Required:  Create a Github account and email us your username (we will add you to our DS4B organization on GitHub) Once you are added to the GitHub DS4B organization, create a new repository (within the organization) for your DS4B coursework. Name it &amp;lt;first name&amp;gt;-&amp;lt;last name&amp;gt;.  Click the “Add a README file” button when initializing the repo. Make the repository private.   Clone the repository on your local machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week02/</guid>
      <description>Week 2: Exploratory Data Analysis  Required:  Download Tableau Desktop software for next week  Get student activation key here   Do some EDA on a dataset of your choice (from sklearn or Kaggle OR check out https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/datasets/)  Add it to Github so we can see! Come up with an initial research question which motivates your exploration of the data. Write 2-3 sentences in your README.md about an interesting fact or correlation you discovered.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week03/</guid>
      <description>Week 3: Data Visualization  Required:  Find 1 example of a good visualization and 1 example of a bad data visualization  Link them in your Github README!  NOTE: links in your README can be created like so [name of the visualization](paste url here)   Also in your README, briefly explain what makes the good visualization good or bad. Think about intuitiveness, data-ink ratio, color scheme, retinal variables, labeling, interactiveness, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week04/</guid>
      <description>Week 4: Neural Networks  Required:  Choose your own adventure homework!  (A) Spend an hour working through the Dataquest Deep Learning Fundamentals  Add 2-3 sentences to your README about key takeaways related to Neural Networks and Deep Learning. If you get to the project or write some cool code, upload your code to Github!   (B) Make a vanilla neural network that can classify MNIST handwritten digits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week05/</guid>
      <description>Week 5: Imaging &amp;amp; Diagnostics  Required:  Do a critical reading of one of the following articles related to convolutional neural networks and/or medical diagnostics.  Deliverables (things to write in your README):  I learned&amp;hellip; After having read the article, I feel optimistic about&amp;hellip; A limitation of the proposed technology is&amp;hellip;   You can pick any article you want, but here are some suggestions if you need a place to start:  The potential for artificial intelligence in healthcare A new approach for classifying coronavirus COVID-19 based on its manifestation on chest X-rays using texture features and neural networks “Solving” Cancer: The Use of Artificial Neural Networks in Cancer Diagnosis and Treatment Plant Disease Detection using Convolutional Neural Network     Do some background research on Corti AI in preparation for our guest speaker (Nicolai Frost Jacobsen) next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week06/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning &amp;amp; Computer Vision  Required:  2-3 paragraph reflection on Nicolai&amp;rsquo;s talk (in README)  Deliverables (things to write in your README):  What is something that you learned? How would you summarize Corti&amp;rsquo;s use of audio-based and text-based models to a friend? Given what you know about the English language (or any other languages), what do you anticipate is most challenging about Natural Language Processing (NLP)? Do you trust deep learning models to process audio input in high stakes contexts (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week07/</guid>
      <description>Natural Language Processing  Required:  Finish NLP workshop (Sentiment Analysis of COVID-19 Vaccine Tweets)!  Deliverables (things to write in your README):  Upload code and any screenshots of interesting graphics/output that you generated Write 2-3 sentences about what you learned about the sentiments and perspectives on the vaccines       Suggested/Just for fun:  Use the Tweepy API to get tweets about J&amp;amp;J and compare sentiments Read articles in the Reading List under Week 7 Data Quest!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/homework/week08/</guid>
      <description>Genetic Algorithms &amp;amp; Gene Sequencing  Required:  Enjoy spring break!    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
