<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modules on Data Science for Biotechnology</title>
    <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modules on Data Science for Biotechnology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 01</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week01/</guid>
      <description>Week 1: Introduction to the Course Links  Class Slides Data Science vs. Computer Science Jamboard Biotechnology Jamboard Jupyter Notebook Setup Creating a GitHub Repository Kaggle Datasets Creating a Simple Linear Regression using sklearn  Jupyter Notebook Installation  OPTION 1: Anaconda &amp;gt; Jupyter Notebooks  $ conda install -c conda-forge notebook  OPTION 2: If you already have Python installed, you can use a software management tool called pip.  $ pip3 install jupyter OR</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 02</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week02/</guid>
      <description>Week 2: Exploratory Data Analysis Links  Class Slides Life Expectancy Dataset Kaggle Datasets Introduction to Pandas Dataframes Google Colab Demo  EDA Checklist  What question(s) are you trying to solve (or prove right / wrong)? What kind of data do you have and how do you treat different types? What&amp;rsquo;s missing from the data and how do you deal with it? Where are the outliers and why should you care about them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 03</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week03/</guid>
      <description>Week 3: Data Visualization Links  Class Slides Guest Speaker: Megan Monroe  Profile Personal Wesbite EventFlow   New York Times covid-19-data  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 04</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week04/</guid>
      <description>Week 4: Neural Networks Links  Class Slides Guest Speaker: Soha Hassoun  Profile Lab Website Slides   TensorFlow Playground Neural Network Playground  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 05</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week05/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week05/</guid>
      <description>Week 5: Imaging and Diagnostics Links  Class Slides Guest Speaker: Fiorenzo Omenetto  Profile Lab Website TED Talk Recent &amp;amp; Relevant Research  Article Video     Digit Recognition with Neural Networks Playground Eyes of Watson: IBM Research Bringing AI to Radiology Watson Visual Recognition  Playgrounds  2D Visualization of a CNN 3D Visualization of a CNN ConvNet Playground: Image Similarity Search  Info and FAQ   CNN Explainer  Demo Video    Imaging Datasets  binarized_mnist: Handwritten Digits bccd: Blood Cells Detection celeb_a: CelebFaces Attributes Dataset aflw2k3d: 3D Facial Landmarks coil100: 7200 Color Images of 100 Objects Cancer Imaging Archive  Phantom FDA   COVID-19 Radiology Dataset (Chest X-Ray and CT)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 06</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week06/</guid>
      <description>Week 6: Deep Learning &amp;amp; Computer Vision Links  Class Slides Guest Lecture by Nicolai Frost Jacobsen (Corti AI) Mid-Semester Feedback Survey Kaggle Dataset DeepFakes Google Cloud Vision Playground Demo        (function(){var qs,js,q,s,d=document,gi=d.getElementById,ce=d.createElement,gt=d.getElementsByTagName,id=&#39;typef_orm&#39;,b=&#39;https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/share.typeform.com/&#39;;if(!gi.call(d,id)){js=ce.call(d,&#39;script&#39;);js.id=id;js.src=b+&#39;widget.js&#39;;q=gt.call(d,&#39;script&#39;)[0];q.parentNode.insertBefore(js,q)}})()   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 07</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week07/</guid>
      <description>Week 7: Natural Language Processing Links  Class Slides AllenNLP Sentiment Analysis Playground TextBlob Documentation NLP Workshop Jupyter Notebook  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 08</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week08/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week08/</guid>
      <description>Week 8: Genetic Algorithms &amp;amp; Gene Sequencing Links  Class Slides Bioinformatics Jamboard BioPython Documentation Gene Sequencing Workshop Jupyter Notebook Genetic Algorithm Walkers (thanks James C!)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 09</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week09/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week09/</guid>
      <description>Week 9: Feature Engineering &amp;amp; Decision Trees Links  Class Slides Decision Tree Workshop Jupyter Notebook  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week10/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week10/</guid>
      <description>Week 10: Data Ethics, Cybersecurity, and Social Justice Links  Class Slides Project Proposals  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/modules/week11/</guid>
      <description>Week 11: Ethics (continued) and Breaking into Data Science Links  Class Slides Data Ethics Film Discussions  The Great Hack  Are there any benefits to social media marketing? Is all data collection unethical? Do you think psychological / behavioral analytics is net positive or net negative? Do you think that social media has shaped your political views? If so, how is that different than your closest friends and family shaping your political views?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
