<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resources on Data Science for Biotechnology</title>
    <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resources on Data Science for Biotechnology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cool Companies</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/companies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/companies/</guid>
      <description>Cool &amp;amp; Relevant Companies  NOTE: we are not sponsoring these companies in any way, shape, or form. This is just to help and hopefully inspire people to dip their toe into the field.
  Illumina Benevolent AI Novo Nordisk Corti AI Reverie Labs Buoy Health Siligon Therapeutics  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datasets</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/datasets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/datasets/</guid>
      <description>Datasets  Healthcare / Medicine / Biotech Realm  Pfizer Vaccine Tweets COVID-19 Open Research Dataset Challenge (CORD-19) Novel Corona Virus 2019 Dataset Heart Disease UCI Chest X-Ray Images (Pneumonia) NeurIPS 2020: Data Science for COVID-19 (DS4C)   Miscellaneous  Datasets that you can load with Python 5 real world datasets for honing your EDA skills 1.88 million US Wildfires Spotify Dataset 1921-2020, 160k+ Tracks 120 years of Olympic History: Athletes and Results Interesting Data to Visualize Plotly Datasets (CSV)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/articles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 23:07:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://datascience4biotech.com/resources/articles/</guid>
      <description>Reading List  Similar to the saying, &amp;ldquo;you are what you eat,&amp;rdquo; in today&amp;rsquo;s world, &amp;ldquo;you are the media you consume.&amp;rdquo; So let&amp;rsquo;s nourish our brains with good food. 🍴🧠
  Week 1: Introduction to the Course  AI &amp;amp; surgery Computer Vision &amp;amp; Self-Driving Cars OpenAI’s new language generator GPT-3 is shockingly good - and completely mindless   Week 2: Exploratory Data Analysis  An Extensive Step by Step Guide to Exploratory Data Analysis EDA Visualization Using Pandas Introduction to Machine Learning Healthcare Fraud Detection with Python   Week 3: Data Visualization  The beauty of data visualization | TED Talk by David McCandless How to Choose the Most Appropriate Chart?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
